荣誉出品
最专业冰火字幕
专注GOT剧集
翻译   陌客之子
翻译   猇亭将
翻译   艾莉娅的缝衣针
翻译   为万世开百事
校对   pksunking
校对   拉拉兄控凯冯
时间轴   poplar
后期    poplar
后期    Jeremy
君临 King's Landing
红堡
Red Keep
恐怖堡 Dreadfort
临冬城
Winterfell
监制    临冬城的狮子
策划    baozhenyuawabi
特别顾问   屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
绝境长城 the Wall
最专业的华语冰火资料站：                         中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
百度冰与火之歌贴吧  &  百度权力的游戏贴吧    联合出品
史诗图书  正统奇幻的圣殿
布拉佛斯
Braavos
弥林
Meereen
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
衣柜字幕组
更多冰火资讯
请扫码关注“黑城堡”微信平台
微信号：HEICHENGBAO
第七集           Mockingbird
仿声鸟
詹姆·兰尼斯特
“弑君者”  御林铁卫队长
提利昂·兰尼斯特
“小恶魔”
我跟他们妥协才让你那忘恩负义的脑袋
I made a deal for you to keep your ungrateful head
和不知感恩的脖子暂时不至于分家
on your ungrateful neck a little while longer.
抱歉 那我该感激咯？
I'm sorry, what am I grateful for?
感激我因为莫须有的罪名
The opportunity to live and die at the Wall
而被发配到长城孤独终老？
as punishment for a crime I did not commit?
是你不想活了 你自己找死
You threw your life away. You threw it away.
这不是个玩笑 你明白吗？
It's not a joke. You understand that, don't you?
这当然是个玩笑 只是不怎么好笑罢了
Of course it's a joke, just not a very funny one.
我——
I couldn't--
我听不下去了
I couldn't listen to her
听她站在那里满嘴谎言
standing there telling her lies.
我做不到
I couldn't do it.
你爱上了个妓女
You fell in love with a whore.
对 我爱上了个妓女
Yes, I fell in love with a whore.
还傻乎乎地以为她也爱上了我
And I was stupid enough to think that she had fallen in love with me.
你做的妥协
That deal you made,
正是父亲想要的
it was everything Father wanted.
明白吗？
You do see that?
他重新让你成了继承人
He gets you back as his heir.
未来的凯岩城公爵
The future Lord of the Rock.
还把我送去黑城堡
And he ships me off to Castle Black,
让我终于可以滚出他的视线
out of sight at last.
一切都那么完美
All so perfect.
让他落得一场空的感觉真好
It felt good to take that from him.
他明知我是无辜的却还是决定牺牲我
He knows I'm innocent and he's willing to sacrifice me anyway.
他愿意牺牲我们任何人
He's willing to sacrifice any of us.
不包括你
Not you.
你是他金光灿灿的儿子
You're the golden son.
你可以杀掉国王 可以没了右手
You could kill a king, lose a hand,
还可以操自己的亲姐姐 不管发生什么你都是金光灿灿的儿子
fuck your own sister, you'll always be the golden son.
小心点
Careful.
我是你最后的朋友了
I'm the last friend you've got.
至少我当面揭露了他们的真面目
At least I got to tell them what they really are.
是啊 精彩的演讲
Yes, brilliant speech.
他们会议论这事好久
They'll be talking about it for days to come.
我还以为你是个现实主义者
I thought you were a realist.
没想到你竟会死于骄傲
Didn't realize you'd die for pride.
别急着现在就放弃我
Don't give up on me just yet.
上次比武审判没有你救我
I survived one trial by combat,
我还活下来了呢
even though you weren't there to save me.
这次我也救不了你
I can't save you this time either.
训练证明
My training has proved
我用左手连个马僮都打不过
that I can't beat a stable boy with my left hand.
你的闯劲都哪去了？
Where's your sense of adventure?
就算你输了
Even if you lose, imagine the look
想象一下父亲的表情吧
on Father's face when you fall.
一剑下去
Our family name snuffed out
我们家族的英名就毁于一旦
with a single swing of the sword.
多么诱人
It is tempting.
瑟曦·兰尼斯特
太后
嗯……
Well...
波隆曾为我而战 这次他也会的
Bronn fought for me once, he'll do it again.
格雷果·克里冈
“魔山”
如果他赢了
If he wins,
我觉得欠他的债
I expect I'll be in his debt
这辈子怕是还不清了
for the rest of my life.
他得能赢
If he wins.
你会帮我去找他吗？
Will you find him for me?
瑟曦打算派谁出战？
Who does Cersei plan on naming as a champion?
我希望是马林·特兰爵士
I hope it's Ser Meryn Trant.
我会很高兴地看着波隆把那傲慢无礼 欺负小孩的家伙开膛破肚
I'd enjoy watching Bronn disembowel that pompous child beater.
不
No.
不是马林爵士
Not Ser Meryn.
来啦 上啊
Go on, move it.
还有你
And you.
上啊
Come on.
饶命
Mercy.
桑铎·克里冈
“猎狗”
艾莉亚·史塔克
求您
Please.
求您了 饶命
Please, mercy.
格雷果爵士 欢迎来到君临
Ser Gregor. Welcome to the capital.
多谢你这么快就赶来了
Thank you for riding here so quickly.
你看起来状态不错
You seem to be in good form.
我要跟谁打？
Who am I fighting?
那重要吗？
Does it matter?
可能有吃的
Could be food.
可能有士兵
Could be soldiers.
你不该这样坐在外面的
You shouldn't be sitting out here like this.
那我坐哪？
Where else to sit?
我想回自己的小屋去
Tried to walk back to my hut,
但伤得太重了
hurt too much.
后来我想起他们烧了我的小屋
Then I remembered they burned my hut down.
“他们”是谁?
Who were "they"?
我早就不多问了
I stopped asking a while ago.
这伤好不了的
That's not gonna get better.
看起来是这样
Doesn't seem so.
糟糕的死法
A bad way to go.
你还没受够吗？
Haven't you had enough?
受够什么？
Of what?
我明白
I know.
该走了
Time to go.
自行了断
Take matters into my own hands.
我想过的
The thought has occurred to me.
那为什么还撑着？
So why go on?
习惯
Habit.
没什么比这个更糟了
Nothing could be worse than this.
什么都没了也许更糟
Maybe nothing is worse than this.
没了就是没了
Nothing isn't better or worse than anything.
也就无所谓糟不糟了
Nothing is just nothing.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我叫艾莉亚
My name is Arya.
艾莉亚·史塔克
Arya Stark.
你是他父亲？
You her father?
我抓了她
Her captor.
带她去姨妈那换赎金
Bringing her to her aunt for ransom.
是啊 公平交易
A fair exchange, that is.
我做每一笔生意的时候都想着
Always held to the notion of fair exchange
要公平交易
in all my dealings.
人弃我取 人取我予
You give me, I give you.
公平
Fair.
均衡
A balance.
不再有什么均衡了
No balance anymore.
"尖牙"
我能喝点什么吗？
Could I have a drink?
死亡是件让人口渴的事
Dying is thirsty work.
多希望是酒
Wish it were wine.
罗尔杰
我也是
So do I.
这是心脏的位置
That's where the heart is.
你要这样杀人
That's how you kill a man.
你他妈干什么？
The fuck you doing?
有人高价买你的人头
There's a price on your head.
看来让国王滚蛋就得摊上这事
Guess that's what the king does when you tell him to fuck off.
国王死了
The king's dead.
他在婚礼上喝了毒酒
He drank poisoned wine at his own wedding.
悬赏你是因为你杀了兰尼斯特家的士兵
The bounty on you is for killing Lannister soldiers.
琼恩·雪诺
守夜人事务官
一百银鹿
100 silver stags.
而你觉得自己能领到赏？
And you thought you were going to collect it?
不会用脑子 是吧
Didn't think very hard, did you?
尤伦带我去长城的时候 你是他的囚犯之一
You were Yoren's prisoners when he was taking me to the Wall.
葛兰
“笨牛” 守夜人游骑兵
他说他要用根棍子狠狠操我
He told me he'd fuck me bloody with a stick.
今天并没有你计划的那么顺利
This day's really not working out the way you planned.
艾里沙·索恩
守夜人教头
杰诺斯·史林特
守夜人
前都城守备队队长
他在你的小名单上吗？
He on your little list?
没办法把他列上
He can't be.
我不知道他的名字
I don't know his name.
你叫什么
What's your name?
白灵
琼恩·雪诺的冰原狼
- 罗尔杰 - 谢了
- Rorge. - Thank you.
你学得挺快
You're learning.
游骑兵归来！
Rangers returning!
他们回来了！
They return!
- 游骑兵归来！- 欢迎
-  Rangers returning! - Greetings.
以为再也见不到你了
Didn't think I'd see you again.
还好吧 琼恩？
All right, Jon?
欢迎归来 兄弟
Welcome back, brother.
雪诺大人
Lord Snow.
艾迪森·托勒特
“忧郁的艾迪” 守夜人事务官
派普尔
“派普” 守夜人
这儿没有这野东西的地方
This is no place for wild beasts.
把它锁起来
Lock him away
要不我就让哈布把它扔进今晚的烩菜里
or I'll let Hobb throw him in tonight's stew.
来吧 白灵
Come on, Ghost.
我们离开时 曼斯的大军正逼近卡斯特的城堡
Mance's army was closing in on Craster's Keep when we left.
我们从欧斯里克山上望见了他们的营火
We saw their campfires from Osric's Hill.
他们将在下次月圆前抵达长城
They'll reach the Wall before the next full moon.
我很惊讶你居然没有骑过去打个招呼
I'm surprised you didn't ride over and say hello.
塞外之王是你的老朋友 对吗？
The King-beyond-the-Wall is your old friend, isn't he?
我们得准备战斗
We need to prepare.
我们早就已经开始准备了
We've been preparing.
我们应该封锁隧道
We should seal the tunnel.
把它用石头和冰块堵起来
Plug it with rocks and ice.
并浇上水使它冻结
Flood it and let it freeze.
那我们怎么巡逻长城以北呢？
And how would we range north?
- 我们不去 - 懦夫
- We wouldn't. -  Coward.
你要我们自断双腿
You would cut off our legs,
自毁双目
pluck out our eyes,
蜷缩在长城后面哆哆嗦嗦
leave us cowering behind the Wall
祈祷风暴过去吗？
hoping for the storm to pass?
我们无法在十万敌军的围攻下守住城门
We can't defend the gate against 100,000 men.
这座城堡已屹立了几千年
This castle has stood for thousands of years.
奥赛尔·亚威克
守夜人的首席工匠
守夜人守卫了它几千年
The Night's Watch has defended her for thousands of years.
几个世纪以来 我们从未封锁过隧道
And in all those centuries, we have never sealed the tunnel.
你见过巨人吗 艾里沙爵士？
Have you ever seen a giant, Ser Alliser?
我亲眼见过
I have.
隧道的大门挡不住他们
The tunnel's gate won't stop them
大门的铁栏足有四尺厚
The bars on those gates are four inches thick.
都是冷轧钢条
Cold-rolled steel.
那挡不住他们
They won't stop them.
告诉我你是属于哪个部门的 雪诺大人
Remind me which order you belong to, Lord Snow.
山姆威尔·塔利
“杀手” 守夜人事务官
事务官
The stewards.
事务官负责维护隧道吗？
Are the stewards responsible for maintaining the tunnel?
不
No.
那是谁负责？
Who would that be?
- 工匠 - 啊 工匠
- The builders. - Ah, the builders.
首席工匠亚威克
First Builder Yarwyck,
雪诺大人提议封锁隧道
Lord Snow here recommends sealing the tunnel,
让我们无法尽忠职守
leaving us unable to carry out our duties
履行身为守夜人兄弟的誓言
as sworn brothers of the Night's Watch.
你赞同他吗？
Do you agree with him?
波隆
骑士
不
No.
鉴于你对野人大军的渊博学识 雪诺大人
Given your deep knowledge of the wildling army, Lord Snow,
你和塔利从今天起每晚都要上长城守夜
you and Tarly will take night duties atop the Wall
直到满月
until the full moon.
继续
Moving on.
首席工匠 我们需要运一百桶沥青上长城
First Builder, we'll need 100 barrels of pitch brought atop the wall.
是
Aye.
大人
My lord.
你穿了身新衣服
You have new clothes.
你喜欢吗？嗯？
Do you like 'em? Eh?
手套是鹿皮的
Gloves are doeskin.
比处女的大腿还柔软呢
Softer than a virgin's thighs.
我几天前就召唤你了
I sent for you days ago.
- 我最近可有点忙 - 忙着做什么？
- I've been a bit busy. - Doing what?
我可悲的单身汉生活即将结束啦
My lonesome bachelor days are over.
我将迎娶洛丽丝·史铎克渥斯女士
I'm to wed Lollys Stokeworth.
洛丽丝·史铎克渥斯？
Lollys Stokeworth?
我可不觉得她合你的口味
She doesn't strike me as your sort of girl.
我不只喜欢一种口味的女人
I wouldn't say I had a single sort of girl.
她是个痴呆
She's dim-witted.
我想要天才 就该娶你了
If I wanted wits, I'd marry you.
当我姐姐促成这场基于真爱的婚姻时
When my sister arranged this love match,
她是否提过洛丽丝还有个姐姐呢？
did she mention that Lollys has an older sister?
法丽丝
Falyse.
哦 我知道她有个姐姐呢
Aye, I did know about the older sister.
你也明白继承权的规矩？
And you understand the rules of inheritance?
法丽丝已经40了 而且没有生育能力
Falyse is 40 and barren.
当她父亲死时 她仍然将继承史铎克渥斯家的城堡
She still gets Castle Stokeworth when her father dies.
的确
She does.
除非她比她父亲更早升天
Unless she happens to perish before her father.
那城堡就是洛丽丝的了
Then Lollys gets the castle.
这又怎么了？女士们常常
What? Ladies fall from their horses
从马上摔下来 跌断她们的小细脖子
and snap their pretty necks all the time.
你和我姐姐还真是绝配呀
You and my sister deserve each other.
那你何必还要到这儿来呢？
Why did you bother to come here?
你曾说过如果任何人让我出卖你
You once said if anyone ever asked me to sell you out,
你都会出双倍的价钱
you'd double their price.
你想要两个妻子还是两座城堡？
Is it two wives you want or two castles?
一个老婆一个城堡就行
One of each will do.
只是要我帮你杀了魔山
But if you want me to kill the Mountain for you,
这城堡非得是个了不起的大家伙
it'd better be a damn big castle.
眼下我无法提供城堡
I'm a bit short on castles at the moment.
但你可以得到我的金子和谢意
But I can offer you gold and gratitude.
我已经有钱了
I have gold.
我拿你的谢意来做什么呢？
What can I buy with gratitude?
兰尼斯特有债必还
You might be surprised.
总有一天我会报答你
A Lannister always pays his debts.
你姐姐也是个兰尼斯特呢
Your sister's a Lannister, too.
我妻子是临冬城的继承人
My wife is heir to Winterfell.
只要能安然度过此次危机
If I emerge from this with my head still on my shoulders,
总有一天我将以她的名义统治北境
I may one day rule the North in her name.
我可以让你分一大杯羹
I could carve you out a big piece of it.
只要 总有一天 到时候
If and may and could.
北地实在太他妈的冷
It's bloody cold up north.
洛丽丝却是暖和柔软
Lollys is soft and warm.
看得见摸得着
And close.
要是我让你选择是跟洛丽丝上床
If I gave you the choice between fucking Lollys
还是跟魔山打架 只怕连眼都不眨
and fighting the Mountain, you'd have your britches down
你就已经脱掉内裤 掏出鸡巴了
and your cock out before I could blink.
你这么怕他？
Does he frighten you so much?
不怕他才怪 你当我是白痴？
I'd be a bloody fool if he didn't frighten me.
他壮得惊人 臂力无穷
He's freakish big and freakish strong.
就一个那般体格的人而言 他的速度已经够可怕了
And quicker than you'd expect for a man of that size.
也许我能赢
Maybe I could take him,
一直围着他转圈 引诱其发力攻击
dance around until he's so tired
直到他连剑也举不动为止
of hacking at me, he dropped his sword,
最后再展开反扑 废掉他的腿
get him off his feet somehow.
但只要一个失误……
But one misstep...
……我就没命了
...and I'm dead.
我凭什么去冒险？
Why should I risk it?
就凭你是我的朋友
Because you're my friend.
对 我是你的朋友
Aye, I'm your friend.
可你什么时候为我冒过生命危险呀？
And when have you ever risked your life for me?
我喜欢你
I like you,
你这个骄纵的小混蛋
pampered little shit that you are.
只是我更爱我自己
I just like myself more.
我理解
I understand.
对不起我只能这么做
I'm sorry it has to be this way.
为什么道歉？
Why are you sorry?
只因为你是个坏家伙
Because you're an evil bastard
没良心也没同情心？
with no conscience and no heart?
这正是我最欣赏你的地方
That's what I liked about you in the first place.
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
“风暴降生” 龙之母
我们有过一段好日子
We had some good days together.
达里奥·纳哈里斯
次子团团长
嗯对
Yes, we did.
你接下来怎么办？
What will you do?
我想我只能亲自出马宰了魔山
I suppose I'll have to kill the Mountain myself.
这难道不该被写成一首伟大的歌谣吗？
Won't that make for a great song?
我希望有一天能听到那首歌
I hope to hear them sing it one day.
你怎么进来的？
How did you get in here?
您的门口戒备森严
Your door is well guarded,
可没人看守窗户
but your window is not.
我游到一里外的小岛上采到了这束花
I swam to an island a mile offshore for these.
别再这么做了
Don't do that again.
我还从未见过不爱野花的女人呢
Never met a woman who didn't like wildflowers.
这是我的私人宅邸
These are my private quarters.
如果我想见你 我会传唤你的
If I want you here, I will summon you.
对不起 女王大人 我就是为了侍奉您而生的
Forgive me, my queen. I live to serve you.
告诉我你为何而来
Tell me why you're here.
我有一个小小的请求
I came to ask a favor.
我在这世上只有两种才能——
I only have two talents in this world--
战争和女人
war and women.
您在弥林逗留 统治这里
You are staying here in Meereen to rule.
这是个明智的选择 我万分赞同
That is a wise decision. I respect it.
然而在弥林 我无法施展我的才华
But here in Meereen, I cannot pursue my talents.
我已命令次子团巡逻街道
I've ordered the Second Sons to patrol the streets
防止仇杀
to stop the revenge killing.
您的命令把我们变成了哨兵
You've ordered us to be night watchmen.
至于女人
And as for women,
弥林有成千上万的女人 可以供你施展自己的才华
there are thousands in Meereen you can pursue.
只有一位女性能令我心醉神迷
There is only one,
可她却对我不理不睬
and she does not want me.
你已向我效忠
You swore me your sword.
我的剑至死都属于您
My sword is yours till the day I die.
所以如果我命令你继续留在弥林
So if I command you to stay in Meereen
巡视街道？
and patrol the streets?
那我就留在弥林 继续巡视街道
I'll stay in Meereen and patrol the streets.
请派我去剿灭您的敌人们
Send me to kill your enemies.
无论什么敌人 身处何方
Any enemy anywhere.
请让我发挥我的才能
Let me do what I do best.
非常好
Very well.
梅丽珊卓
光之王的“红袍祭司”
赛丽丝·佛罗伦
史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩之王后
请发挥你的专长
Do what you do best.
脱了你的衣服吧
Take off your clothes.
噢
Oh.
王后大人 请进
Come in, my queen. Please.
女士 我不想打扰您
I didn't mean to disturb you, my lady.
您的造访永远不算打扰
You could never disturb me.
我只是想在我们离开之前和您谈一谈
I just wanted to speak with you before we left.
请您帮我拿一下那边的小瓶好吗？
Could you bring me that vial over there?
蓝色的瓶子
The blue one.
不不不 不是那一瓶
No, no, no. Not that one.
那一瓶我建议您碰都不要碰
You don't even want to touch that one.
旁边的那瓶
Next to it.
就是那瓶
That's the one.
我今早观察火焰时
When I looked into the flames this morning,
光之王对我说
the Lord spoke to me.
他说
He said,
“今夜之后 很长一段时间内你将无法享受舒适的沐浴”
"Tonight, you will have your last good bath in a long while.
“请好好珍惜”
Make it count."
开个玩笑
A joke.
也许这并不那么可笑
Not a very good one, I'm afraid.
很好笑 只是我——
It was. I--
我并不擅长幽默
humor isn't my strength.
那是因为大部分笑话都是谎言
That's because most jokes are lies
而你一心一意只追求真相
and you're devoted to the truth.
如果它们都是谎言 夫人 不应当设法远离它们吗？
If they're lies, my lady, aren't they best avoided?
并不总是这样的
Not always.
这些粉末与药剂
Most of these powders and potions
大多都是谎言
are lies.
诱使人们相信他们目睹了光之王神迹的谎言
Deceptions to make men think they witnessed our Lord's power.
一旦他们进入了它的光芒里 他们就将意识到这些谎言的真面目——
Once they step into his light, they will see the lie for what it was--
谎言只是引领人们接近真理的小把戏
a trick that lead them to the truth.
在篝火中放一点点这种粉末
A pinch of this powder in a bonfire
会引发一条火蛇嚎叫着冲向天空
will send a flaming column screaming towards the sky.
这种粉末会制造黑色的烟雾
And this one creates a black smoke
把最勇敢的男子汉都吓得尿裤子
that will make the bravest man piss himself with fear.
只要在任何男人的酒中滴一点这个
And a drop of this in any man's wine
就将使他为情欲痴狂
will drive him wild with lust.
你在史坦尼斯身上用过这个吗？
Did you use it with Stannis?
没有
No.
别伤心
Don't be upset.
男人们从不渴望他们已经拥有的东西
Men never crave what they already have.
不过是肉欲
It's only flesh.
本能的需求
It needs what it needs.
只要是为了光之王
No act done in service of the Lord
一切行为都不是罪孽
can ever be called a sin.
每天我都感谢真神将你带给我们
I thank God every day for bringing you to us.
也将史坦尼斯带给你
And Stannis to you.
他想把希琳也带上
He wants to bring Shireen with us.
我认为那可能并不是个好主意
I think that would be ill-advised.
也许你注意到了 我们的女儿有异教徒倾向
My daughter has heretical tendencies, as you're well aware.
我不确定她是否真心怀疑真神 抑或她只是希望与我做对
I don't know if her doubt is real or simply meant to spite me,
不过无论如何 她都最好留在家里
but whichever the case, she should stay home.
我理解你的考虑
I understand how you feel.
嗯
Hmm.
但这不可能
But that is impossible.
乔拉·莫尔蒙
“大熊”
为什么?
Why?
您根本不需要粉末或者药剂 王后陛下
You don't need powders and potions, my queen.
您不需要谎言
You don't need lies.
您的信仰已足够坚定
You are strong enough to look into the Lord's light
足以自行在光之王的圣火中看到真相
and see his truth for yourself.
尽管很严苛
However harsh it is.
尽管对我们来说很难解读
However hard for us to understand.
您也并不需要我的协助
You don't need my help,
但我很快就需要您的帮助
but I will need yours soon.
我们起航时 需要带上您的女儿希琳公主一起
When we set sail, your daughter must be with us.
光之王需要她
The Lord needs her.
安达尔人乔拉
Jorah the Andal.
你是来觐见女王陛下的吗?
Are you here to see our queen?
她现在心情很好
She's in a good mood.
卡丽熙
Khaleesi.
- 你终于来了 - 比某人来得晚
- You're here early. - Later than some.
你不赞同?
You don't approve?
这并不是关乎于赞同 而是关乎于信任
It's not a question of approval, it's a question of trust.
你既不赞同我也不信任我
You neither approve nor trust.
我又能做什么?他是雇佣兵
Why would I? The man's a sellsword.
在你对我哥哥宣誓效忠以前
Didn't you fight for the Golden Company
你不是也曾受雇于黄金团吗?
before pledging your sword to my brother?
的确如此
I did.
我信任你
I trust you.
达里奥·纳哈里斯杀了另外两名团长
Daario Naharis killed his captains
把他们的人头抛在您脚下 仅仅是因为他厌倦了听令于他们
and dumped their heads at your feet when he grew tired of their commands.
您怎么能信任那种人?
How could you ever have faith in a man like that?
我从未信任过他
I could never have faith in a man like Daario.
所以我才把他派往次子团 协同收复渊凯
That's why I've sent him and the Second Sons to retake Yunkai.
- 您真的这么做了? - 当然
- You have? - I have.
您不在那里统治 卡丽熙
Without you there to rule, Khaleesi,
我担心善主们只是在那里等待时机
I fear the masters will simply bide their time,
等待入侵者离开就重夺渊凯控制权
wait for the invaders to leave and reassert control.
所以我才命令达里奥处决渊凯善主 不放过任何一个
That is why I've ordered Daario to execute every master in Yunkai.
善主们将婴儿从母亲的怀里夺走 生生撕裂
The masters tear babies from their mothers' arms.
将成千上万的小男孩肢解
They mutilate little boys by the thousands.
把小女孩培养成妓院里取悦老男人的玩物
They train little girls in the art of pleasuring old men.
他们把人当畜生 你也说过
They treat men like beasts, as you said yourself.
把善主们囚禁起来 然后成批地屠宰
Herding the masters into pens and slaughtering them by the thousands
这同样是把人当畜生
is also treating men like beasts.
您解放的那些奴隶
The slaves you freed,
他们只懂野蛮暴虐
brutality is all they've ever known.
若是想教化他们
If you want them to know something else,
只能树立榜样 以身作则
you'll have to show it to them.
那奴隶贩子又该得到什么？仁慈？
And repay the slaves with what? Kindness?
罚款？口头警告？
A fine? A stern warning?
把您的所有敌人都视为邪恶的 的确很便捷
It's tempting to see your enemies as evil, all of them,
但在战争中 善与恶是并存的
but there's good and evil on both sides in every war ever fought.
让牧师们去讨论善恶吧
Let the priests argue over good and evil.
奴隶制可是真切存在的
Slavery is real.
我有能力推翻它 我就要这么做
I can end it. I will end it.
幕后的势力我也会一并推翻
And I will end those behind it.
我也曾贩奴 卡丽熙
I sold men into slavery, Khaleesi.
而你现在要做的是帮我解放他们
And now you are helping me show them to freedom.
要是奈德·史塔克对我也像您对待渊凯的善主那样
I wouldn't be here to help you if Ned Stark had done to me
我就没机会在这里协助您了
what you want to do to the masters of Yunkai.
那人第二天就来觐见我 商议厚葬他的父亲
The man who came to me the other day about burying his father.
西茨达拉·佐·洛拉克?
Hizdahr zo Loraq?
他会协同次子团
He will accompany the Second Sons
然后作为我的使节前往渊凯
and serve as my ambassador to Yunkai.
他会告诉善主们弥林发生的一切
He will tell the masters what has happened in Meereen.
并让善主们认清形势
He will explain the choice they have before them.
要么在我建立的新世界里生存
They can live in my new world
要么就只能跟着旧世界一起灭亡
or they can die in their old one.
对了 达里奥走前让他来见我
Well, go and catch Daario before he leaves.
告诉他我改主意了
Tell him I changed my mind.
是的 卡丽熙
Yes, Khaleesi.
不对
No.
告诉他是你使我改主意了
Tell him you changed my mind.
老鼠洞
Rat cunts.
该死的妓女
Fucking whore.
你不该那样清理伤口
You're doing it wrong.
这么严重的咬伤应该用火烧
You need to burn away that horrible bit there.
否则会感染化脓
Otherwise it's gonna get infected and fester.
我知道你不喜欢火 但你这么做是不行的--
I know you don't like fire, but if you don't do it right--
不要火
No fire.
就一眨眼的事儿
It'll only take a second.
- 不会很疼的 - 别过来！
- It won't hurt that much. - No fire!
别提这事儿了
Shut up about it.
什么都别提了
Shut up about everything.
多亏了你 如今我变成了活钱袋
Thanks to you, I'm a walking bag of silver
到哪儿都能看着兰尼斯特家的人
anywhere the Lannisters hold sway.
在哪儿哪儿被围堵
Which is everywhere between where we are now
去哪儿哪儿都被阻截
and where we're going.
我比村里被你捅死那只猪还蠢
I'm as stupid as that hog you stuck back in the village,
被切被刺被啃
getting myself cut and stabbed and bitten.
给我多少钱我都不愿干这破事
No reward is worth this much trouble.
我要是从没注意过你就好了
Wish I'd never laid eyes on you.
你说过你哥给了你那把剑
You say your brother gave you that sword.
我哥却烧了我的脸
My brother gave me this.
就像你说的 是挺久以前了
It was just like you said a while back.
他把我的脸按进燃烧的火盆
Pressed me to the fire
就像一块多汁的羊排
like I was a nice juicy mutton chop.
他为什么这么做?
Why?
他以为我偷了他的玩具
Thought I stole one of his toys.
我没偷 我只是拿着玩儿
I didn't steal it. I was just playing with it.
那感觉可真他妈可怕
The pain was bad.
闻起来更可怕
The smell was worse.
最可怕的是 是我的亲哥哥这么对我的
But the worst thing was that it was my brother who did it.
我爸还为他撑腰
My father, who protected him...
对别人说是我床单着了火
told everyone my bedding caught fire.
波德瑞克·派恩
布蕾妮的侍从
布蕾妮·塔斯
“美人”
你以为只有你是孑然一身?
You think you're on your own?
我来帮你洗净伤口吧
Let me wash it out
而且无论如何得帮你缝上
and help you sew it up at least.
“热派”
稍微犒劳下自己无伤大雅
Bit of comfort never hurt anyone.
我们在沟里呆了好几个星期了
We've been sleeping in ditches the last few weeks.
就睡一晚羽毛床吧
I think we can treat ourselves to a featherbed for the night
你也不用做饭了
and a hot meal not cooked by you.
完全同意 小姐
Couldn't agree more, my lady.
别期待有丝质睡衣就好
Just don't start expecting silk underclothes.
我可没你以前的主人那么阔绰
Not working for your former lord any longer.
- 是的 小姐  - 别喝多了
- Yes, my lady. - Don't get drunk.
好的 小姐
No, my lady.
还需要点其他的吗?
Can I get you anything else?
这些就很好了 谢谢
No, this will do nicely, thank you.
腰子派很好吃
Kidney pie is wonderful.
感谢称赞
Thanks.
这是我最拿手的
I do my best.
腰子派美味的秘诀在于材料
A good kidney pie is all about the ingredients.
面粉 猪油 水 鸡蛋 牛奶
Flour, lard, water, eggs, milk.
都很简单 但肉的选取就讲究了
Easy enough. But the meat,
时机是否合适 得把手放在一块上好的牛后腿肉上才能判断
peacetime or not, getting your hands on a good bottom round steak
而选取牛犊的腰子也是技术活
and calves' kidneys is not easy.
我是说 有些人用普通的老腰子来做派
I mean, some people settle for plain old beef kidneys.
这样的人什么菜都做不好
Got no right to cook anything, them.
哦 还有卤汁
Oh, and the gravy.
说起卤汁我就激动
Don't get me started on the gravy.
很难做好
Very difficult to get right.
很多人就是因为做不好卤汁才放弃做派的
See, a lot of people give up on the gravy.
这可不能放弃啊
You cannot give up on the gravy.
没有卤汁的派还能叫派吗
No gravy, no pie.
就这么简单
Simple as that.
铠甲不错 您是一名骑士吗?
That's nice armor. Are you a knight?
不是
No.
哦 我还以为穿着铠甲的都是骑士
Oh, it's just people with armor are usually knights.
一般都是这样的 你们是从君临来的吧？
Generally speaking. From King's Landing, though, aren't you?
我老家就是君临跳蚤窝
From there myself originally. Flea Bottom born and bred.
什么风把你们吹到这儿来了？
What brings you to these parts?
我们在找人
We're looking for someone.
那人有什么特征? 也许来过这里
Someone in particular? Maybe they came in here.
很多人都来这里 昨天我们还有17个--
A lot of people come in here. Just the other day we had 17--
一个女孩 高挑 红发 很漂亮
A girl, tall, red hair, very pretty.
她叫珊莎·史塔克 但可能用的是化名
Her name is Sansa Stark, but she may be using a different name.
史塔克家族的?
Starks?
哪个史塔克家族 临冻城的吗?
What, like them lot from "Winterhell"?
没 从没见过
No, ain't seen anyone like that.
我听说他们是叛徒
I heard they was all traitors.
这儿可不欢迎叛徒
Don't need no traitors in here.
我以性命向他们的母亲 凯特琳·史塔克起誓
I pledged my life to their mother Catelyn Stark.
我发誓我会带她的女儿们回家
I swore to her I'd bring her daughters home.
还想再来点儿腰子派吗？
Sure I can't get you a bit more kidney pie?
你想说什么?
What?
没什么 小姐
It's nothing, my lady.
没什么说的你脸就不会拧成那样啦
You wouldn't be screwing your face up like that if it was nothing.
我无意冒犯 小姐 真的没什么
Don't want to offend, my lady. Truly, I don't.
你还没好看到能冒犯我呢
You're not interesting enough to be offensive.
兰尼斯特家族的人想要珊莎小姐
The Lannisters want Lady Sansa.
兰尼斯特家族很有钱
The Lannisters have money.
人们为了钱什么都干得出来
People kill for money.
我觉得我们不该向其他人透露
I don't think we should be telling people
我们在找珊莎夫人这件事
we're searching for Lady Sansa.
小姐 大人 我能说句话吗?
My lady. My lord. Could I have a word?
你想说什么? 不要腰子派了
What about? Not kidney pie.
您看起来是位正派的小姐
You seem like a proper lady.
可以信赖
Someone who could be trusted.
我的确没见过珊莎·史塔克
I never met no Sansa Stark.
但我认识她妹妹
But I know her sister...
艾莉亚
Arya.
艾莉亚·史塔克的父亲被处决后 她就不见踪影了
No one's seen Arya Stark since her father was beheaded.
大家都以为她死了
She's presumed dead.
我上次跟她说话时她还没死
She weren't when I last spoke to her.
- 什么时候？ - 跟着守夜人北上时
- When was that? - Heading up north with the Night's Watch.
和您一样 她打扮得像个男孩子
She was all dressed up as a boy.
只是您比她多了铠甲
Like your ladyship, only without the armor.
她化名为阿利
Going by the name Arry.
- 她怎么了? - 这个嘛--
- So what happened to her? - Well--
长话短说
The quick version.
兰尼斯特家族的人抓住了我们
The Lannisters took us prisoner.
我们逃走了
We escaped.
兄弟会的人又抓住了我们
The Brotherhood took us prisoner.
把我卖到了旅店
They sold me to the innkeep.
他们本打算带艾莉亚·史塔克去奔流城找她妈妈换赎金
They were gonna sell Arya to her mother at Riverrun
跟关着的另一个人一起
along with another prisoner.
又高又丑 满嘴脏话
Big ugly fellow. Foul mouth
脸长得像烧焦一半的火腿
and a face like a half-burnt ham.
- 满脸凶相  - 猎狗
-  Not friendly. - The Hound.
就是他
That's the one.
如果你们找到她 能把这个给她吗？
If you find her, could you give her this?
她很喜欢我之前给她的那个
She liked the last one I gave her,
但这个做得更好
but, well, this one turned out better.
唔 你刚才说什么来着？
Um, you were saying?
她失去了母亲 外公也去世了
Her mother's dead, grandfather's dead,
瓦德·佛雷成了新的奔流城主
Walder Frey is the new lord of Riverrun.
兄弟会不会去奔流城的
The Brotherhood isn't going to Riverrun.
他们应该是带着她去鹰巢城了 小姐
They'll take her to the Eyrie, my lady.
为什么去那里?
Why the Eyrie?
她的姨妈 莱莎·艾林
Her aunt, Lysa Arryn.
凯特琳·史塔克的妹妹
Catelyn Stark's sister.
她是艾莉亚唯一在世而且有钱的亲人
She's Arya's last living relative with money.
她恨兰尼斯特家族的人
She hates the Lannisters.
奥柏伦·马泰尔
“红毒蛇” 多恩亲王
提利昂大人让我记住了
Lord Tyrion made sure I knew
各个家族的结亲跟结仇的情况
which house married which and who hated who.
珊莎没准也在那里
Sansa could be there, too.
是啊 小姐
Aye, my lady.
也许在那里
Could be.
你确定吗?
You sure about this?
不
No.
我还以为您这会儿已经回妓院了
I imagined you'd be back at the brothel at this hour.
我昨天还真跟个绝对正点的金发妞玩儿了会儿
I did spend some time with an absolutely stunning blonde the other day.
嗯 看得出来
Mm, do tell.
这地方真是啥垃圾都有
I've got every kind of filth down here
就是没我喜欢的
except the kind I like.
你姐姐
Your sister.
噢
Oh.
瑟曦召见了我
Cersei approached me.
我们谈了很多关于她女儿的事情
We spoke a great deal about her daughter.
她很担心她的女儿
How worried your sister is about her.
她竭力掩饰
She was trying very hard to pretend
假装她不是来让我反对你的
she had not come to sway me against you.
我想也许她自己都这么认为
I think she may have even believed it herself.
假意吐露真情来达到欺骗的目的
Making honest feelings do dishonest work
这是她的惯用伎俩之一
is one of her many gifts.
她很难掩饰自己的真实意图
It was difficult for her to hide her true intentions.
很少遇到一位兰尼斯特家的人
It is rare to meet a Lannister
像我一样对弄死兰尼斯特家的人如此热心
who shares my enthusiasm for dead Lannisters.
她巴不得看到你死
She desperately wants to see you killed.
她不用劳驾您
She didn't need to bother you.
看起来这事由我自己解决就行了
It looks as though I've taken care of that myself.
当我人头落地时
The joy she will feel
她会无比开心
when my head leaves my neck.
她早就盼着这一刻了
She's wanted this for a long time.
是的 我知道
Yes, I know.
我们见过面 你和我
We met, you and I.
好多年以前
Many years ago.
如果见过 我会记得的
I think I would have remembered that.
不可能 你刚刚出生
Unlikely. You had just been born.
我父亲带着我和姐姐伊莉亚
Our father brought me and my sister Elia with him
一起造访凯岩城
on a visit to Casterly Rock.
那是我第一次离开多恩
My first time away from Dorne.
我一点也不喜欢凯岩城
I didn't like anything about the Rock.
讨厌那里的食物 天气
Not the food, not the weather,
还有你们的口音
not your accents.
什么都不喜欢
Nothing.
而最让我失望的
But the biggest disappointment...
是你
you.
您家族和我家族的共同点比你们愿意承认的要多
You and my family have more in common than you might admit.
从多恩过来 一路上
The whole way from Dorne
听到的话题全是那个怪物
all anyone talked about was the monster
泰温·兰尼斯特刚出生的儿子
that had been born to Tywin Lannister.
头有两个身体那么大
A head twice the size of his body,
两腿间长着一根尾巴
a tail between his legs,
还有爪子 一只眼睛是红色的
claws, one red eye,
不仅有男人的命根子 还有女子的阴道
the privates of both a girl and a boy.
那可就省却不少烦恼
That would have made things so much easier.
当我们见到你姐姐时 她答应一定会满足我们的好奇心
When we met your sister, she promised she would show you to us.
我们每天都问
Every day we would ask.
每天她都说"快了"
Every day she would say, "Soon."
后来她和你哥哥
Then she and your brother
带我们去你的婴儿室
took us to your nursery and...
她向我们展示了怪物
she unveiled the freak.
你的头有点大
Your head was a bit large.
你的胳膊和腿有点小
Your arms and legs were a bit small,
但没爪子
but no claw.
没红眼睛 两腿之间没有尾巴
No red eye. No tail between your legs.
只有一个粉红的小命根子
Just a tiny pink cock.
我们没打算掩饰自己的失望
We didn't try to hide our disappointment.
"那不是个怪物" 我对瑟曦说
"That's not a monster," I told Cersei.
"只是个婴儿"
"That's just a baby."
她回答 "他杀了我妈妈"
And she said, "He killed my mother."
然后用力拧你的小命根子
And she pinched your little cock so hard,
像要把它扯下来
I thought she might pull it off.
直到你哥哥让她住手
Until your brother made her stop.
"有什么关系" 她对我们说
"It doesn't matter," she told us.
"大家都说他活不长
"Everyone says he will die soon.
我希望他们说的是对的
I hope they are right.
他早该死了"
He should not have lived this long."
哎
Well...
瑟曦迟早会得到她想要的
sooner or later, Cersei always gets what she wants.
那我想要的怎么办？
And what about what I want?
正义
Justice
为了我姐姐和她的孩子们
for my sister and her children.
如果你想要正义
If you want justice,
你来错了地方
you've come to the wrong place.
我不同意
I disagree.
我来对了
I've come to the perfect place.
我想要将那些伤害我的人绳之以法
I want to bring those who have wronged me to justice.
珊莎·史塔克
小恶魔的妻子
那些伤害我的人全在这里
And all those who have wronged me are right here.
我会先从格雷果·克里冈爵士开始
I will begin with Ser Gregor Clegane,
他杀了我姐姐的孩子们
who killed my sister's children
然后就着满手鲜血强奸了她
and then raped her with their blood still on his hands
最后又杀了她
before killing her, too.
我会做你的代理骑士
I will be your champion.
劳勃·艾林
“乖罗宾” 鹰巢城公爵
琼恩·艾林独子
你好 罗宾
Hello, Robin.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我在搭建我的家 临冬城
I'm building my home, Winterfell.
至少我是这么认为的
At least I think I am.
我很久没有回到那里了
I haven't been back there in a very long time.
你当初为什么离开?
Why did you leave?
说来话长
It's a long story.
我一直待在鹰巢城
I stay here in the Eyrie.
母亲说路上危险 我得保证自己的安全
Mother says it's dangerous on the roads and I have to keep myself safe
因为我是谷地守护者
because I'm the Lord of the Vale
谷地守护者是一个非常重要的人物
and the Lord of the Vale is a very important person.
是的 你当然是
Yes, you certainly are.
你什么时候回家?
When will you go back?
也许永远回不去了
Probably never.
我的家人不住在那里了
My family doesn't live there anymore
它被烧毁了
and someone burned it down.
哦
Oh.
临冬城有月门吗?
Does Winterfell have a Moon Door?
恐怕没有
No, I'm afraid not.
临冬城不在山上 是在平地上
It's not high up in the mountains. It's down on the ground.
听起来很危险
That sounds dangerous.
- 那你们怎么让人飞? - 我们不会
- How do you make people fly? - We don't.
那你们怎么处置那些不好的人
What do you do with all the bad people
可怕的人和讨厌的人?
and the scary people and the people you don't like?
我从不处置他们
I never did anything with them at all.
在我们那儿 女孩不会参与这些事
Girls didn't take part in that where I came from.
我是谷地守护者
Well, I'm Lord of the Vale.
等我长大了 谁敢烦我 我就让谁飞
When I grow up, I'll be able to fly anybody who bothers me.
培提尔·贝里席
“小指头” 赫伦堡公爵
或者烦你的人 等我们结婚以后
Or you. When we get married,
如果你讨厌谁 可以告诉我
you can tell me if you don't like somebody
咱就给他们带到这儿来
and then we can bring them back here and, whoosh!
嗖地一声从月门飞出去
Right through the Moon Door.
听起来不错
I like the sound of that.
让我们在你的临冬城里搭建一座月门
Let's put a Moon Door in your Winterfell.
好吧
All right.
可以建在这个高塔里
It can go in here in this big tower.
小心 你毁了它
Careful. You've ruined it.
现在我要整个儿重新搭建了
Now I'm going to have to rebuild the whole thing.
- 不是我毁的 - 是你
- I didn't ruin it. - You did.
早就毁了 因为它没有月门
It was already ruined because it didn't have a Moon Door.
我在修理
I was fixing it.
把东西推倒可不是修理
Knocking things down isn't fixing them.
- 而是毁了它 - 不是我毁的!
- It's ruining them. - I didn't ruin it!
- 你在犯傻气 - 不是我毁的!
- You're being stupid. - I didn't ruin it!
罗宾 我很抱歉 我--
Robin, I'm sorry, I--
孩子
Children.
- 我打了他 - 是的 我看到了
-  I hit him. - Yes, I saw.
我不该那么做
I shouldn't have done that.
不 他母亲该这么做
No, his mother should have
早该这么做
a long time ago.
就把它当成正确的一步
Consider it a step in the right direction.
如果他告诉莱莎姨妈...
If he tells Aunt Lysa...
让我来操心莱莎姨妈
Let me worry about Aunt Lysa.
我想记起临冬城是什么样的
I was trying to remember what everything looked like.
我永远也见不到它了
I'll never see it again.
在现在和永远不之间 有无尽的可能
A lot can happen between now and never.
如果你想建造一个更好的家
If you want to build a better home,
首先你必须推倒旧家
first you must demolish the old one.
你杀死乔佛里的真正原因是什么?
Why did you really kill Joffrey?
告诉我为什么
Tell me why.
我比你想象的更爱你母亲
I loved your mother more than you could ever know.
如果有机会 对于那些伤害了我们所爱的人
Given the opportunity, what do we do to those
我们该怎么对付他们?
who've hurt the ones we love?
在一个更好的世界里
In a better world,
一个爱能战胜
one where love
力量和职责的世界里
could overcome strength and duty,
你也许是我的孩子
you might have been my child.
但我们并未生在那样的世界里
But we don't live in that world.
莱莎·徒利
凯特琳·徒利的妹妹
琼恩·艾林的遗孀
小指头的妻子
你比当年的她更美
You're more beautiful than she ever was.
贝里席大人...
Lord Baelish...
叫我培提尔
Call me Petyr.
你想见我 莱莎姨妈?
You wanted to see me, Aunt Lysa?
到这儿来 珊莎
Come here, Sansa.
你知道从这里掉下去有多高吗?
Do you know how far the fall is?
不知道
No.
我也不知道到底有多高
Neither do I, precisely.
几百英尺
Hundreds of feet.
很有趣
It's fascinating
从这么高的地方掉下去 落到石头上后尸体会怎么样
what happens to bodies when they hit the rocks from such a height.
冲击力会把他们摔得粉碎
The impact breaks them right apart.
就像鸡蛋掉到地上
Like eggs dropped on the floor.
有些尸块会保持完整
Sometimes pieces remain intact.
你会发现一颗头在那里
You'll find the head sitting on its own.
每根头发都还在
Every hair in place.
蓝眼睛空洞无物
Blue eyes staring at nothing.
我知道你做了什么
I know what you did.
我很抱歉 莱莎姨妈
I'm so sorry, Aunt Lysa.
我知道我不该打罗宾 我保证不会有下次了--
I never should have hit Robin, I know it. I promise it won't happen--
别跟我忸怩作态 小婊子
Don't be coy with me, you little whore.
你吻了他 你吻了培提尔
You kissed him. You kissed Petyr.
- 我没有 你没明白 - 我看见你了
- I didn't. You don't understand. - I saw you.
你别想说谎 我亲眼看见的
You can't lie to me because I saw it with my own eyes.
- 他吻了我 我推开了 - 骗子!
- He kissed me. I pulled away. - Liar!
婊子! 他是我的!
Whore! He is mine!
我父亲 我丈夫 我姐姐
My father, my husband, my sister,
他们都妨碍了我们 现在他们全死了
they all stood between us and now they're all dead.
妨碍我和培提尔的人就是这个下场
That's what happens to people who stand between Petyr and me.
往下看!
Look down!
往下看! 往下看! 往下看!
Look down! Look down! Look down!
莱莎!
Lysa!
放开她
Let her go.
你想要她?
You want her?
这个又蠢又笨的孩子?
This empty-headed child?
放开她
Let her go.
她和她妈一样 她永远不会爱你的
She's just like her mother. She'll never love you.
我为你撒谎
I lied for you.
我为你杀人
I killed for you.
你为什么要带她来这里? 为什么?
Why did you bring her here? Why?
我会把她送走
I'll send her away.
我以性命发誓
I swear on my life.
我向诸神发誓
I swear to all the gods.
放开她 莱莎
Let her go, Lysa.
哦 我可爱的老婆
Oh, my sweet wife.
我可爱又无知的老婆
My sweet, silly wife.
我只爱过一个女人...
I have only loved one woman...
我一生中
only one,
只爱过一个
my entire life.
只爱你姐姐
Your sister.
衣柜字幕组出品